TYLER BECK

Software Engineer

I'm an experienced React/Front End software engineer with a strong background in web development and a passion for building user-friendly, efficient, and scalable applications. Having years of experience with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and other web development technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at 100Devs, Los Angeles, CA

October 2021 — Present

- Created numerous Front End React web applications, with proper use of hooks, state management/Redux, testing via Jest, Git/Github, while optimizing performance and speed for the client
- Collaborated with a team of developers to build full stack and responsive web applications, in which I optimized build times by 45% by refactoring, using progressive rendering, and performing testing/debugging.
- Built semantically structured full stack web applications using Javascript on front end (React) and back end (Node.js/Express) utilizing Git/GitHub for version control as well as database management (MongoDB) & authorization.
- Applied Agile methodologies like SCRUM for project management with a team of developers.

Freelance Full Stack Web Developer | USA

January 2021 — Present

Created full stack web applications and static websites for different clients generating 55% increase in website traffic and 40% increase in revenue generated.

Physical Therapist at Drayer Physical Therapy

October 2020 — October 2021

Evaluated, diagnosed, and treated 100's of patients, using personal experience, expert literature, and advanced coursework to resolve musculoskeletal dysfunctions while optimizing billing to generate 25% more revenue over expected values.

Recent Projects:

GoTravel (React, Redux, Node/Express, MongoDB) — A responsive full stack (MERN) web application to allow users to sign up/login, make posts about their personal vacation experiences with pictures, creating a beautiful dashboard of all experiences.

TB-Electronics Store (React, Nextjs, Stripe, CSS, HTML) – Fully functional eCommerce store, with Stripe integration, easily customizable and easy to use, with individual product pages including add to cart/buy-now functionality.

Feliz Travels (React, CSS3, Javascript) – Responsive travel journal showing off beautiful locations to visit using React, with use of components, props, local API integration, which can be easily adapted to use with database/RESTful API retrieval.

Other Projects: Stargazer: beautiful pictures of the universe with NASA API integration. Bookworm: a web app allowing users to add/delete books with LocalStorage integration, and others...

CONTACT

570-470-5212

softwaretpd2035@gmail.com

https://tylerbeck-webdev.netlify.app/

https://github.com/Mussina123

linkedin.com/in/tyler-beck-webdev

SKILLS

React

Javascript (ES6)

Redux

Node/Express

API Development

CSS/Bootstrap/Tailwind

HTML

Git/GitHub

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

OOP

Web Accessibility

Time Management

Organized & Analytical

Team Player

EDUCATION

WIDENER UNIVERSITY

2017-2020

Doctor of Physical Therapy (DPT)

WEST CHESTER UNIVERSITY

2013-2017

Bachelor Degree: Kinesiology